var CARDS_PREFIX = 'german-';
var CARDS_DATA =[{"id":"body-Körper","category":"body","question":"'the body'","answer":"der Körper"},
{"id":"arm-Arm","category":"body","question":"'the arm'","answer":"der Arm"},
{"id":"eye-Auge","category":"body","question":"'the eye'","answer":"das Auge"},
{"id":"cheek-Backe","category":"body","question":"'the cheek'","answer":"die Backe"},
{"id":"belly-Bauch","category":"body","question":"'the belly'","answer":"der Bauch"},
{"id":"leg-Bein","category":"body","question":"'the leg'","answer":"das Bein"},
{"id":"chest-Brust","category":"body","question":"'the chest'","answer":"die Brust"},
{"id":"finger-Finger","category":"body","question":"'the finger'","answer":"der Finger"},
{"id":"foot-Fuss","category":"body","question":"'the foot'","answer":"der Fuss"},
{"id":"chin-Kinn","category":"body","question":"'the chin'","answer":"das Kinn"},
{"id":"knee-Knie","category":"body","question":"'the knee'","answer":"das Knie"},
{"id":"bone-Knochen","category":"body","question":"'the bone'","answer":"das Knochen"},
{"id":"head-Kopf","category":"body","question":"'the head'","answer":"der Kopf"},
{"id":"lip-Lippe","category":"body","question":"'the lip'","answer":"die Lippe"},
{"id":"stomach-Magen","category":"body","question":"'the stomach'","answer":"der Magen"},
{"id":"nail-Nagel","category":"body","question":"'the nail'","answer":"der Nagel"},
{"id":"mouth-Mund","category":"body","question":"'the mouth'","answer":"der Mund"},
{"id":"nose-Nase","category":"body","question":"'the nose'","answer":"die Nase"},
{"id":"ankle-Fussgelenk","category":"body","question":"'the ankle'","answer":"das Fussgelenk"},
{"id":"brain-Gehirn","category":"body","question":"'the brain'","answer":"das Gehirn"},
{"id":"hair-Haar","category":"body","question":"'the hair'","answer":"das Haar"},
{"id":"neck-Hals","category":"body","question":"'the neck'","answer":"der Hals"},
{"id":"hand-Hand","category":"body","question":"'the hand'","answer":"die Hand"},
{"id":"wrist-Handgelenk","category":"body","question":"'the wrist'","answer":"das Handgelenk"},
{"id":"skin-Haut","category":"body","question":"'the skin'","answer":"die Haut"},
{"id":"heart-Herz","category":"body","question":"'the heart'","answer":"das Herz"},
{"id":"jaw-Kiefer","category":"body","question":"'the jaw'","answer":"der Kiefer"},
{"id":"ear-Ohr","category":"body","question":"'the ear'","answer":"das Ohr"},
{"id":"back-Rücken","category":"body","question":"'the back'","answer":"der Rücken"},
{"id":"shoulder-Schulter","category":"body","question":"'the shoulder'","answer":"die Schulter"},
{"id":"forehead-Stirn","category":"body","question":"'the forehead'","answer":"die Stirn"},
{"id":"tooth-Zahn","category":"body","question":"'the tooth'","answer":"der Zahn"},
{"id":"toe-Zehe","category":"body","question":"'the toe'","answer":"die Zehe"},
{"id":"tongue-Zunge","category":"body","question":"'the tongue'","answer":"die Zunge"},
{"id":"face-Gesicht","category":"body","question":"'the face'","answer":"das Gesicht"},
{"id":"cheek-Wange","category":"body","question":"'the cheek'","answer":"die Wange"},
{"id":"jacket-Jacke","category":"clothing","question":"'the jacket'","answer":"die Jacke"},
{"id":"dress-Kleid","category":"clothing","question":"'the dress'","answer":"das Kleid"},
{"id":"skirt-Rock","category":"clothing","question":"'the skirt'","answer":"der Rock"},
{"id":"sweater-Pullover","category":"clothing","question":"'the sweater'","answer":"der Pullover"},
{"id":"shirt-Hemd","category":"clothing","question":"'the shirt'","answer":"das Hemd"},
{"id":"T-shirt-T-Shirt","category":"clothing","question":"'the T-shirt'","answer":"das T-Shirt"},
{"id":"sock-Socke","category":"clothing","question":"'the sock'","answer":"die Socke"},
{"id":"shoe-Schuh","category":"clothing","question":"'the shoe'","answer":"der Schuh"},
{"id":"boot-Stiefel","category":"clothing","question":"'the boot'","answer":"der Stiefel"},
{"id":"sandal-Sandale","category":"clothing","question":"'the sandal'","answer":"die Sandale"},
{"id":"swimsuit-Badeanzug","category":"clothing","question":"'the swimsuit'","answer":"der Badeanzug"},
{"id":"underwear-Unterwäsche","category":"clothing","question":"'the underwear'","answer":"die Unterwäsche"},
{"id":"pants-Hose","category":"clothing","question":"'the pants'","answer":"die Hose"},
{"id":"raincoat-Regenmantel","category":"clothing","question":"'the raincoat'","answer":"der Regenmantel"},
{"id":"coat-Mantel","category":"clothing","question":"'the coat'","answer":"der Mantel"},
{"id":"orange-orange","category":"colors","question":"'orange'","answer":" orange"},
{"id":"pink-rosa","category":"colors","question":"'pink'","answer":" rosa"},
{"id":"purple-violett","category":"colors","question":"'purple'","answer":" violett"},
{"id":"blue-blau","category":"colors","question":"'blue'","answer":" blau"},
{"id":"yellow-gelb","category":"colors","question":"'yellow'","answer":" gelb"},
{"id":"red-rot","category":"colors","question":"'red'","answer":" rot"},
{"id":"black-schwarz","category":"colors","question":"'black'","answer":" schwarz"},
{"id":"brown-braun","category":"colors","question":"'brown'","answer":" braun"},
{"id":"gray-grau","category":"colors","question":"'gray'","answer":" grau"},
{"id":"white-weiß","category":"colors","question":"'white'","answer":" weiß"},
{"id":"green-grün","category":"colors","question":"'green'","answer":" grün"},
{"id":"street-Straße","category":"directions","question":"'the street'","answer":"der Straße"},
{"id":"avenue-Allee","category":"directions","question":"'the avenue'","answer":"die Allee"},
{"id":"north-Norden","category":"directions","question":"'the north'","answer":"der Norden"},
{"id":"south-Süden","category":"directions","question":"'the south'","answer":"der Süden"},
{"id":"east-Osten","category":"directions","question":"'the east'","answer":"der Osten"},
{"id":"west-Westen","category":"directions","question":"'the west'","answer":"der Westen"},
{"id":"husband-Mann","category":"family","question":"'the husband'","answer":"der Mann"},
{"id":"son-Sohn","category":"family","question":"'the son'","answer":"der Sohn"},
{"id":"father-Vater","category":"family","question":"'the father'","answer":"der Vater"},
{"id":"brother-Bruder","category":"family","question":"'the brother'","answer":"der Bruder"},
{"id":"grandfather-Großvater","category":"family","question":"'the grandfather'","answer":"der Großvater"},
{"id":"uncle-Onkel","category":"family","question":"'the uncle'","answer":"der Onkel"},
{"id":"nephew-Neffe","category":"family","question":"'the nephew'","answer":"der Neffe"},
{"id":"cousin-Vetter","category":"family","question":"'the cousin'","answer":"der Vetter"},
{"id":"daughter-Tochter","category":"family","question":"'the daughter'","answer":"die Tochter"},
{"id":"mother-Mutter","category":"family","question":"'the mother'","answer":"die Mutter"},
{"id":"sister-Schwester","category":"family","question":"'the sister'","answer":"die Schwester"},
{"id":"grandmother-Großmutter","category":"family","question":"'the grandmother'","answer":"die Großmutter"},
{"id":"aunt-Tante","category":"family","question":"'the aunt'","answer":"die Tante"},
{"id":"niece-Nichte","category":"family","question":"'the niece'","answer":"die Nichte"},
{"id":"wife-Frau","category":"family","question":"'the wife'","answer":"die Frau"},
{"id":"children-Kinder","category":"family","question":"'the children'","answer":"die Kinder"},
{"id":"bread-Brot","category":"food","question":"'the bread'","answer":"das Brot"},
{"id":"pepper-Pfeffer","category":"food","question":"'the pepper'","answer":"der Pfeffer"},
{"id":"salt-Salz","category":"food","question":"'the salt'","answer":"das Salz"},
{"id":"ice-Eis","category":"food","question":"'the ice'","answer":"das Eis"},
{"id":"vinegar-Essig","category":"food","question":"'the vinegar'","answer":"der Essig"},
{"id":"oil-Öl","category":"food","question":"'the oil'","answer":"das Öl"},
{"id":"sugar-Zucker","category":"food","question":"'the sugar'","answer":"der Zucker"},
{"id":"butter-Butter","category":"food","question":"'the butter'","answer":"die Butter"},
{"id":"cake-Kuchen","category":"food","question":"'the cake'","answer":"der Kuchen"},
{"id":"egg-Ei","category":"food","question":"'the egg'","answer":"das Ei"},
{"id":"ice cream-Eis","category":"food","question":"'the ice cream'","answer":"das Eis"},
{"id":"rice-Reis","category":"food","question":"'the rice'","answer":"der Reis"},
{"id":"salad-Salat","category":"food","question":"'the salad'","answer":"der Salat"},
{"id":"soup-Suppe","category":"food","question":"'the soup'","answer":"die Suppe"},
{"id":"honey-Honig","category":"food","question":"'the honey'","answer":"der Honig"},
{"id":"snack-Imbiss","category":"food","question":"'the snack'","answer":"der Imbiss"},
{"id":"cheese-Käse","category":"food","question":"'the cheese'","answer":"der Käse"},
{"id":"pie-Torte","category":"food","question":"'the pie'","answer":"die Torte"},
{"id":"bean-Bohne","category":"food","question":"'the bean'","answer":"die Bohne"},
{"id":"potato-Kartoffel","category":"food","question":"'the potato'","answer":"die Kartoffel"},
{"id":"tea-Tee","category":"food-drinks","question":"'the tea'","answer":"der Tee"},
{"id":"juice-Saft","category":"food-drinks","question":"'the juice'","answer":"der Saft"},
{"id":"water-Wasser","category":"food-drinks","question":"'the water'","answer":"das Wasser"},
{"id":"coffee-Kaffee","category":"food-drinks","question":"'the coffee'","answer":"der Kaffee"},
{"id":"wine-Wein","category":"food-drinks","question":"'the wine'","answer":"der Wein"},
{"id":"beer-Bier","category":"food-drinks","question":"'the beer'","answer":"das Bier"},
{"id":"soft drink-Limonade","category":"food-drinks","question":"'the soft drink'","answer":"die Limonade"},
{"id":"milk-Milch","category":"food-drinks","question":"'the milk'","answer":"die Milch"},
{"id":"breakfast-Frühstück","category":"food-eating","question":"'the breakfast'","answer":"das Frühstück"},
{"id":"lunch-Mittagessen","category":"food-eating","question":"'the lunch'","answer":"das Mittagessen"},
{"id":"dinner-Abendessen","category":"food-eating","question":"'the dinner'","answer":"das Abendessen"},
{"id":"glass-Glas","category":"food-eating","question":"'the glass'","answer":"das Glas"},
{"id":"fork-Gabel","category":"food-eating","question":"'the fork'","answer":"die Gabel"},
{"id":"spoon-Löffel","category":"food-eating","question":"'the spoon'","answer":"der Löffel"},
{"id":"knife-Messer","category":"food-eating","question":"'the knife'","answer":"das Messer"},
{"id":"napkin-Serviette","category":"food-eating","question":"'the napkin'","answer":"die Serviette"},
{"id":"plate-Teller","category":"food-eating","question":"'the plate'","answer":"der Teller"},
{"id":"silverware-Besteck","category":"food-eating","question":"'the silverware'","answer":"das Besteck"},
{"id":"dishes-Geschirr","category":"food-eating","question":"'the dishes'","answer":"das Geschirr"},
{"id":"fruit-Obst","category":"food-fruit","question":"'the fruit'","answer":"das Obst"},
{"id":"pineapple-Ananas","category":"food-fruit","question":"'the pineapple'","answer":"die Ananas"},
{"id":"apple-Apfel","category":"food-fruit","question":"'the apple'","answer":"der Apfel"},
{"id":"apricot-Aprikose","category":"food-fruit","question":"'the apricot'","answer":"die Aprikose"},
{"id":"banana-Banane","category":"food-fruit","question":"'the banana'","answer":"die Banane"},
{"id":"pear-Birne","category":"food-fruit","question":"'the pear'","answer":"die Birne"},
{"id":"strawberry-Erdbeere","category":"food-fruit","question":"'the strawberry'","answer":"die Erdbeere"},
{"id":"raspberry-Himbeere","category":"food-fruit","question":"'the raspberry'","answer":"die Himbeere"},
{"id":"cherry-Kirsche","category":"food-fruit","question":"'the cherry'","answer":"die Kirsche"},
{"id":"lime-Limone","category":"food-fruit","question":"'the lime'","answer":"die Limone"},
{"id":"lemon-Zitrone","category":"food-fruit","question":"'the lemon'","answer":"die Zitrone"},
{"id":"orange-Orange","category":"food-fruit","question":"'the orange'","answer":"die Orange"},
{"id":"peach-Pfirsisch","category":"food-fruit","question":"'the peach'","answer":"der Pfirsisch"},
{"id":"grape-Traube","category":"food-fruit","question":"'the grape'","answer":"die Traube"},
{"id":"steak-Steak","category":"food-meat","question":"'the steak'","answer":"das Steak"},
{"id":"chicken-Huhn","category":"food-meat","question":"'the chicken'","answer":"das Huhn"},
{"id":"fish-Fisch","category":"food-meat","question":"'the fish'","answer":"der Fisch"},
{"id":"ham-Schinken","category":"food-meat","question":"'the ham'","answer":"der Schinken"},
{"id":"meat-Fleisch","category":"food-meat","question":"'the meat'","answer":"das Fleisch"},
{"id":"roast-Braten","category":"food-meat","question":"'the roast'","answer":"der Braten"},
{"id":"veal-Kalbfleisch","category":"food-meat","question":"'the veal'","answer":"das Kalbfleisch"},
{"id":"lamb-Lammfleisch","category":"food-meat","question":"'the lamb'","answer":"das Lammfleisch"},
{"id":"beef-Rindfleisch","category":"food-meat","question":"'the beef'","answer":"das Rindfleisch"},
{"id":"pork-Schweinefleisch","category":"food-meat","question":"'the pork'","answer":"das Schweinefleisch"},
{"id":"bacon-Speck","category":"food-meat","question":"'the bacon'","answer":"der Speck"},
{"id":"sausage-Wurst","category":"food-meat","question":"'the sausage'","answer":"die Wurst"},
{"id":"poultry-Geflügel","category":"food-meat","question":"'the poultry'","answer":"das Geflügel"},
{"id":"duck-Ente","category":"food-meat","question":"'the duck'","answer":"die Ente"},
{"id":"chicken-Huhn","category":"food-meat","question":"'the chicken'","answer":"das Huhn"},
{"id":"turkey-Truthahn","category":"food-meat","question":"'the turkey'","answer":"der Truthahn"},
{"id":"pumpkin-Kürbis","category":"food-vegetables","question":"'the pumpkin'","answer":"der Kürbis"},
{"id":"olive-Olive","category":"food-vegetables","question":"'the olive'","answer":"die Olive"},
{"id":"lettuce-Salat","category":"food-vegetables","question":"'the lettuce'","answer":"der Salat"},
{"id":"tomato-Tomate","category":"food-vegetables","question":"'the tomato'","answer":"die Tomate"},
{"id":"onion-Zwiebel","category":"food-vegetables","question":"'the onion'","answer":"die Zwiebel"},
{"id":"vegetable-Gemüse","category":"food-vegetables","question":"'the vegetable'","answer":"das Gemüse"},
{"id":"cauliflower-Blumenkohl","category":"food-vegetables","question":"'the cauliflower'","answer":"der Blumenkohl"},
{"id":"pea-Erbse","category":"food-vegetables","question":"'the pea'","answer":"die Erbse"},
{"id":"cucumber-Gurke","category":"food-vegetables","question":"'the cucumber'","answer":"die Gurke"},
{"id":"carrot-Karotte","category":"food-vegetables","question":"'the carrot'","answer":"die Karotte"},
{"id":"cabbage-Kohl","category":"food-vegetables","question":"'the cabbage'","answer":"der Kohl"},
{"id":"window-Fenster","category":"house","question":"'the window'","answer":"das Fenster"},
{"id":"room-Zimmer","category":"house","question":"'the room'","answer":"das Zimmer"},
{"id":"bathroom-Badezimmer","category":"house","question":"'the bathroom'","answer":"das Badezimmer"},
{"id":"bedroom-Schlafzimmer","category":"house","question":"'the bedroom'","answer":"das Schlafzimmer"},
{"id":"living room-Wohnzimmer","category":"house","question":"'the living room'","answer":"das Wohnzimmer"},
{"id":"kitchen-Küche","category":"house","question":"'the kitchen'","answer":"die Küche"},
{"id":"hallway-Flur","category":"house","question":"'the hallway'","answer":"der Flur"},
{"id":"furniture-Möbel","category":"house","question":"'the furniture'","answer":"die Möbel"},
{"id":"wall-Wand","category":"house","question":"'the wall'","answer":"die Wand"},
{"id":"ceiling-Decke","category":"house","question":"'the ceiling'","answer":"die Decke"},
{"id":"door-Tür","category":"house","question":"'the door'","answer":"die Tür"},
{"id":"floor-Boden","category":"house","question":"'the floor'","answer":"der Boden"},
{"id":"left-links","category":"directions","question":"'left'","answer":" links"},
{"id":"right-recht","category":"directions","question":"'right'","answer":" recht"},
{"id":"far-weit","category":"directions","question":"'far'","answer":" weit"},
{"id":"near-in Nähe","category":"directions","question":"'near'","answer":" in Nähe"},
{"id":"January-Januar","category":"months","question":"'January'","answer":" Januar"},
{"id":"February-Februar","category":"months","question":"'February'","answer":" Februar"},
{"id":"March-März","category":"months","question":"'March'","answer":" März"},
{"id":"April-April","category":"months","question":"'April'","answer":" April"},
{"id":"May-Mai","category":"months","question":"'May'","answer":" Mai"},
{"id":"June-Juni","category":"months","question":"'June'","answer":" Juni"},
{"id":"July-Juli","category":"months","question":"'July'","answer":" Juli"},
{"id":"August-August","category":"months","question":"'August'","answer":" August"},
{"id":"September-September","category":"months","question":"'September'","answer":" September"},
{"id":"October-Oktober","category":"months","question":"'October'","answer":" Oktober"},
{"id":"November-November","category":"months","question":"'November'","answer":" November"},
{"id":"December-Dezember","category":"months","question":"'December'","answer":" Dezember"},
{"id":"Monday-Montag","category":"weekdays","question":"'Monday'","answer":" Montag"},
{"id":"Tuesday-Dienstag","category":"weekdays","question":"'Tuesday'","answer":" Dienstag"},
{"id":"Wednesday-Mittwoch","category":"weekdays","question":"'Wednesday'","answer":" Mittwoch"},
{"id":"Thursday-Donnerstag","category":"weekdays","question":"'Thursday'","answer":" Donnerstag"},
{"id":"Friday-Freitag","category":"weekdays","question":"'Friday'","answer":" Freitag"},
{"id":"Saturday-Samstag","category":"weekdays","question":"'Saturday'","answer":" Samstag"},
{"id":"Sunday-Sonntag","category":"weekdays","question":"'Sunday'","answer":" Sonntag"}];
